Saraba chikyuu yo, tabidatsu fune wa
Farewell Earth, a ship is taking off
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
A New Voyage
Space Battleship
Ucyuu no kanata Iskandar he unmei seoi ima tobitatsu
It's about to take off to Iscandar carrying the fate of humanity
Kanarazu koko he kaette kuru to
We'll return for sure
Te wo furu hito ni egao de kotae
Smile back at the people waving their hands
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Iscandar...
The twin planet to our Garmillas.
It's the planet of love, which plots
the salvation of all intelligent life.
It's the guiding light and spiritual
support for the culture of Garmillas.
Starsha, the first time
I saw you, you looked so mature.
What were you trying
to tell me at that moment…
Visual signal received from Evacuation Fleet 28.
Long live, Desler.
We'll see you in the new world, Galman.
Tell them that I pray for their safe voyage.
Yes, sir.
This marks one third of our population,
but I hear many are still refusing to migrate.
The trip to the home planet
of Gamilas will take us two weeks.
Your Excellency, if you appeal to those that remain on Garmillas, surely the skeptics will change their tune…
You mean after hearing from
someone aboard this ship, Talan ?
My sincerest apologies !
Applying the noble blue color to Your Excellency's
command ship will be done with as soon as possible.
Sometimes red is good.
Garmillas is currently undergoing a mass migration.
They're at odds with an interstellar
alliance called the Bolar Federation.
You must be aware of that.
The situation is tense.
As members of the Earth Defense Force, you have a very important responsibility at a time like this.
Defense Fleet 65, with the space battleship Yamato as its flagship, will begin a long voyage to the Magellanic Cloud...
...in order to escort our delegation
to Garmillas and Iscandar.
In addition, this long trip will serve as an
important training mission for the new crew.
As you know, the Yamato is known for prioritizing human lives over military readiness.
It represents our policy of peace...
It's not an oversight.
Someone must've deliberately falsified personnel data.
It could've been Domon himself,
so that he could sneak on board the Yamato.
He was a top achiever at the academy.
If not for his father's case, he would've
been assigned to the Yamato anyway.
He could be dangerous, Captain Kodai.
He may have infiltrated the
Yamato with a grudge against you.
Declaration !
We pledge to do everything we can to complete our duties to maintain Earth's peace and prosperity.
Domon Ryusuke, representing the 38th class of students of the Space Defense Academy.
Wait.
As Captain of the Yamato,
I have an order for you.
Domon Ryusuke, take the
helm for the ship's departure.
We're departing early.
Unexpected things happen
on the battlefield. Hurry up !
What's going on ?
Why is Ryusuke on the first bridge ?
How would I know ?
Domon, what did you do ?
Hey, newbie !
Sir !
Departure position, remember ?
Our men are all on board.
Yamato hasn't changed a bit.
Is that so ?
All is well.
I was supposed to lead the departure.
If you mess up...
Trying to kick me out...?
I won't quit, no matter what.
Tactical officer Domon, you have control.
Tactical officer Domon, I have control.
Prepare for departure.
Captain Sanada, is it true that a
newbie is going to fly the Yamato ?
It's too late to call this a surprise prank...
Ship functions all green.
All personnel in position.
Auxiliary power is online.
Domon, we can go any time.
Relax.
Relax your shoulders.
Auxiliary engine, channel power.
Auxiliary engine, channeling power.
Relax, Tokugawa.
C...contact
Auxiliary engine, low speed rev at 1600.
Output balance of both thrusters is perfect.
Ahead slow, 0.5.
Auxiliary engine, from contact 2 to contact 3.
Wave motion engine,
open the cylinder shut-down valve.
Shut-down valve...
Wait, Tasuke.
What's the ship's current speed ?
It's four. Hurry up.
Input done !
Opening the shut-down valve.
What ? The Yamato stalled ?
I'll slow down the ship.
No, keep going. All ahead flank.
Change of formation.
Hyuga and Asuka will go ahead.
Acknowledged.
As expected, their response is...
Idiot ! It's speed 3 !
What did you learn in school ?!
Tokugawa, don't let your father down !
Right.
Man, I was perfect in practice.
What am I doing ?
Is the ship alright ?
It's so unstable.
Calm down, and take a seat.
It's strange that two people who were enemies
only a few years ago are now on the same ship.
There're many issues of concern, but this peace....
...mustn't be lost.
Fly wheel activated.
Ten seconds to ignition
of the wave motion engine.
Nine...
...eight...
...seven...
...six...
...five...
...four...
...three...
Geez...
...two...
Wave motion energy charge
Wave motion core pressure
...one...
Contact and ignition.
Yamato, take off !
What's wrong, Domon ?
Hey, what're you doing ?
Accelerate and take off.
Yamato is not taking off.
Oh my gosh, oh my gosh...
What is she doing ?
At this rate, she'll run aground.
Father...
I...
I...!
Look, Tsubasa.
The Yamato...
Dad's ship is leaving.
Since Earth left fighting behind...
chikyū wa itsushika tatakai wasure
...it's been covered with shining green
kagayaku midori ni tsutsu mare ta
Fear and sorrow have left people's hearts
osore mo nageki mo kokoro o hanare
And all that's left is a gentle song
yasashī uta dake ga nagarete ta
Stop time, so that peace will remain
jikan yo tomare heiwa no mamade
Now is the age of dreams
ima kono yume no kono jidai
Remember Yamato !
When the red star passes over the galaxy
ginga ni akai hoshi ga sugete
When the darkness falls once again
futatabi kageri ga sashita toki
New faces, new determinations and...
aratana kao to aratana ketsui
...the new Yamato begins their journey
aratana Yamato ga tabi ni tatsu
What ?!
You let someone like him helm the Yamato ?!
What's wrong with you ?
Isn't it apparent that Domon
illegally accessed personnel data ?
Get rid of him at once.
Why did you...?
You thought they wouldn't figure it out ?
You're such a moron, Domon.
Doing this alone...
We didn't find any explosives
or abnormal objects in your body.
You're healthy, just like any young man.
Domon Ryusuke...
I admit to falsifying my background
and personal information.
Your military status will be revoked.
Understood ?
Domon deserves to be a Yamato crewman because of his achievements and talent.
As captain, I made that judgment.
I don't want to lose a talented individual by raising unwarranted suspicion because of his father.
Are you serious, Captain Kodai ?
It appears to me that your
nasty habit has surfaced once again.
Shouldering responsibility all on your own…
…a nasty habit indeed.
Pardon my intrusion.
Would you like another cup ?
A shuttle has left the Ginga,
heading for the Yamato as planned.
Engineering officer Yabu and Domon...
We're exchanging a
mutineer for a hacker, huh ?
That's enough.
I'm sorry.
Discharged, huh ?
It can't be helped.
He's looked tormented ever since his father died.
He stopped smiling like that.
What was he trying to do on the Yamato ?
I don't know, but it could be just like us.
“Don't let your father down.”
It can't be the same.
That idiot embarrassed the 38th's students.
Fireboat
Domon !
I'm Hirata, the resource department chief.
Have you cooked rice before ?
Yes.
Okay.
How about rice balls ?
Sure.
Then you're qualified.
As of now, you're assigned to the
resource department as a quartermaster.
Huh ?
We have some brass on board for this trip,
and we have to cook all of their meals by ourselves.
Our situation's so dire that
we could use help from cats.
I have the Captain's permission.
Well then I...
Here.
Cooking supports everyone,
and it's a tough battlefield.
Prepare yourself.
Let's go.
Um...
I have no pleasantries to
exchange with an outsider.
Sorry, Yabu.
Ms. Niimi...
Please understand that the current
atmosphere is not exactly welcoming.
I'll take the GeshVar-related material
to the technical analysis room.
Aye.
I heard the troublemaker has
been made into a rice cook.
He's not the only problem.
Lack of human resources and fast-paced training...
Newbies all tend to get carried away.
This Yamato fleet is like a newborn baby...
...who needs to stand on its own two
feet before reaching outer space.
It's not going to be easy, Captain Kodai.
Training Day 1:
Air Wing Mock Combat Training
Yankee leader to all units. We'll begin mock combat.
The new models are tough.
Stay sharp.
A training session before even
meeting up with the Yamato ?
I'll use this chance to kick their butts.
Don't get cocky, Sakamoto.
Roger that.
Here they come.
Hotel leader to all units,
let's give them a warm welcome.
There they are !
What the...?!
Yankee 3, Sakamoto !
Don't push too hard !
If you crash into a asteroid, you're dead !
That's why it's fun.
Shot down three.
Not bad.
Sakamoto Shigeru, huh ?
A type of guy who rushes to death.
Training Day 7:
Space Cavalry Descent Training
Target is Titan, a moon of the old Saturn.
Coordinate with the Yamato air unit to descend.
Raiden, if you cut corners just because
this is a drill, I'll kick your ass !
Thanks for your advice.
It's been a while, Caroline.
I'll make sure you're well escorted.
Whatever.
Let's touch down first.
Okay.
That's Saturn...?
It's on Ginga's restoration plan
schedule, but it's a long ways off.
I wish Iscandar would lend
us another Cosmo Reverse...
Please don't upset Starsha
with such careless comments.
Alright !
Training Day 14:
Anti-ship Combat Training
Prepare for anti-ship battle.
Right after a warp ? Is he a demon ?
All stations, prepare for anti-ship battle exercise.
Aerial defense unit, move to the
operation zone as soon as possible.
Hotel leader, clear for take-off.
Okay, good luck.
Missiles hit to aft.
Massive shock to the hull.
Asuka's in firing range.
Fire !
Dammit !
Asuka used its defensive shield again !
Combat Tactical Chief Kitano,
the timing was slow !
I'm sorry !
Combat rations !
I'm leaving it right here.
Hurry, get going !
Combat rations !
I brought your combat rations !
Could that be...
Did you figure out what
it was just by looking at it ?
Oh, I'm sorry. I have to go.
Youth is quite something.
Daddy can’t afford to fall behind.
When can we leave ?
Our escort hasn't arrived yet ?
Leeza, why did you bring that ?
I can't just leave them behind.
Flowers aren't edible.
You can't eat them.
I won't.
Listen, I...
But you eat anything, even insects.
How could you...?!
I have a baby inside me.
A baby ?
You'll be half-related because your
father, Yabu, is not from Zaltz.
Even so...
A new sibling ?!
Congratulations, Mom.
Thanks, you guys.
When we get to Planet Galman...
What was that ?
Yamato, a New Departure!!
Episode 2
The Last Day of Garmillas
Next Time
Behind the sorrow...
kanashimi no ushiro de itsumo
Susumu Kodai:
Yuki Mori:
Daisuke Shima:
Shiro Sanada:
Yasuo Nanbu:
Yoshikazu Aihara:
Kenichiro Ohta:
Ryusuke Domon:
Tasuke Tokugawa:
Heiji Bando:
Miyako Kyozuka:
Caroline Raiden:
Shigeru Sakamoto:
Tetsuya Kitano:
Toru Hoshina:
Sakezo Sado:
Daisuke Ono
Houko Kuwashima
Kenichi Suzumura
Hochu Otsuka
Kenji Akabane
Kazuto Kokubu
Yuki Chiba
Tasuku Hatanaka
Nobuhiko Okamoto
Wataru Hatano
Tomo Muranaka
Chitose Morinaga
Kento Ito
Ryuichi Kijima
Motoki Takagi
Shigeru Chiba
Miku Saijo:
Kaoru Niimi:
Mikage Kiryu:
Isao Enomoto:
Susumu Yamazaki:
Hajime Hirata:
Shiori Nagakura:
Akira Yamamoto:
Sho Sawamura:
Hiroki Shinohara:
Makoto Kato:
Tetsuo Kuri:
Shoji Wakasa:
Namio Sakamaki:
Haruo Nishina:
Analyzers:
Satomi Moriya
Aya Hisakawa
Eriko Nakamura
Kenjiro Tsuda
Hiroshi Tsuchida
Fumihide Ise
Kazusa Amagai
Rie Tanaka
Yuya Chikaki
Daisuke Hirakawa
Rina Sat
Hiroki Maeda
Hiromichi Tezuka
Takashi Kondo
Kenta Miyake
Cho
...happiness is always waiting for you
tsugi wa shiawase ga matteiru
Osamu Yamanami:
Loren Barrel:
Kotetsu Serizawa:
Yarb Skerge:
Balna Skerge:
Oddo Skerge:
Leeza Skerge:
Leza Skerge:
Abelt Desler:
Gadel Talan:
Masashi Ebara
Masaki Terasoma
Tessho Genda
Cho
Mie Nonozaki
Tomo Muranaka
Chitose Morinaga
Eriko Nakamura
Koichi Yamadera
Kotaro Yakamura
Let's turn that fairy tale into truth
sonna guuwa wo shinjitsuni kaemashou
You whisper with a spark in your eye
anata no me ga mabushisouni sasayaku
You don’t dream to get hurt
yume wo miru no wa kizutsuku tame janai
Love still shines even now
ai wa ima mo hikari
There’s only one prayer
tada hitotsu no inori
The future has already begun
mirai wa mou hajimatte iru